Transcript and translation
from Aria Sky http://youtu.be/I0DrWFblrhs
Sung by Hu Wei Na (胡维纳)
The snow glows white on the mountain tonight,
白雪发亮今夜铺满山上
bái xuě fā liàng jīn yè pū mǎn shān shàng
The glowing snow covers the mountain tonight,
not a footprint to be seen
没有脚印的地方
méi yǒu jiǎo yìn de dì fāng
there are no footprints in this place
A kingdom of isolation,
孤立的王国很荒凉
gū lì de wāng guó hěn huāng liáng
This lone kingdom is so desolate
and it looks like I'm the queen
我是这里的女皇
wǒ shì zhè lǐ de nǚ huáng
I'm the queen in this place
The wind is howling like this swirling storm inside
风在呼啸像心里的风暴一样
fēng zài hū xiào xiàng xīn lǐ de fēng bào yī yàng
The wind is howling like the storm inside of me
Couldn't keep it in, heaven knows I tried
只有天知道我受过的伤
zhǐ yǒu tiān zhī dào wǒ shòu guò de shāng
Only heaven knows what I've been through
Don't let them in, don't let them see
别让他们进来看见
Bié ràng tā men jìn lái kàn jiàn
Don't let them in, don't let them see
Be the good girl you always had to be
做好女孩就像你的从前
zuò hǎo nǚ hái jiù xiàng nǐ de cóng qián﻿
Be the good girl as you did before
Conceal, don't feel, don't let them know
躲藏不让他们看见
duǒ cáng bū ràng tā mén kàn jiàn
Hide and don't let them see
Well, now they know!
已被发现
yǐ beì fā xiàn
But now they know!
Let it go, let it go!
随它吧随它吧
suí tā ba suí tā ba
Let it go, let it go!
Can't hold it back any more!
回头已没办法
huí tóu yǐ méi yǒu bàn fǎ
Now there's no way back
Let it go, let it go!
随它吧随它吧
suí tā ba suí tā ba
Let it go, let it go!
Turn away and slam the door!
一转身不再牵挂
yī zhuǎn shēn bū zài qiān guà
Turn back and don't worry any more!
I don't care what they're going to say
我不管他们想说的话
wǒ bū guǎn tā mén xiǎng shuō de huà
I don't care about what they have to say
Let the storm rage on
任风吹雨打
rèn fēng chuī yǚ dǎ
Let the wind howl and rain fall
The cold never bothered me anyway.
反正冰天雪地我也不怕
fǎn zhèng bing tiān xuě dì wǒ yě bū pà
I don't fear the ice and snow anyway.
It's funny how some distance
这一点点的距离
zhè yī diǎn diǎn de jǜ lí
This very little distance
Makes everything seem small
让一切变精致
ràng yī qiè biàn jīn zhì
Makes everything so fine
And the fears that once controlled me
曾经困扰我的恐惧
céng jing kùn ráo wǒ de kǒng jǚ
The fear that once bothered me
Can't get to me at all!
会远离我回忆
huì yuǎn lí wǒ huí yì
Will go away from my memory
It's time to see what I can do
现在开始让我看见
xiàn zài kāi shǐ ràng wǒ kàn jiàn
Starting now, what makes me see
To test the limits and break through
是我的突破和极限
shì wǒ de tū pò hé jǐ xiàn
are my break through and limits
No right, no wrong, no rules for me
不分对错没有极限
bū fen duì cuò méi yǒu jǐ xiàn
No right, no wrong, without limits
I'm free!
向前
xiàng qián
I'm going on
Let it go, let it go!
随它吧随它吧
suí tā ba suí tā ba
Let it go, let it go!
I am one with the wind and sky
跟风和天空对话
gēn fēng hé tiān kōng duì huà
Speak out with the wind and the sky
Let it go, let it go!
随它吧随它吧
suí tā ba suí tā ba
Let it go, let it go!
You'll never see me cry
眼泪不再掉下
yǎn lèi bū zài diào xià
My tears won't ever drop
Here I stand, and here I'll stay,
这个家让我留下
zhè ge jiā ràng wǒ liú xià
This is the home which let me stay
Let the storm rage on...
任风吹雨打
rèn fēng chuī yǚ dǎ
Let the wind howl, and the rain fall...
My power flurries through the air and to the ground
我力量从空气中扩散到地上
wǒ lì liàng chón kōng qì zhōng kuò sàn dào dì shàng
My power spreads from the air into the ground
My soul is spiralling in frozen fractals all around
我灵魂盘旋在冰块各种不同形状
wǒ líng hún pán xuán zài bing kuài gè zhǒng bū tóng xíng zhuàng
My soul is spiraling as ice in different shapes and forms
And one thought crystallizes like an icy blast
我思想结晶变成锋利的闪光
wǒ sī xiǎng jié jīng biàn chéng fēng lì de shǎn guāng
My thought crystallizes into sharp flashes
I'm never going back
我永不回头看
wǒ yǒng bū huí tóu kàn
I will never look back
The past is in the past!
以往会被埋葬
yǐ wǎng huì beì mái zàng
I'll bury all the past!
Let it go, let it go!
随它吧随它吧
suí tā ba suí tā ba
Let it go, let it go!
And I'll rise like the break of dawn
让我在曙光中升华
ràng wǒ zài shǔ guāng zhōng shēng huá
Let me rise at the break of dawn
Let it go, let it go!
随它吧随它吧
suí tā ba suí tā ba
Let it go, let it go!
That perfect girl is gone
让完美被蒸发
ràng wán měi beì zhēng fā
Let the perfection evaporate
Here I stand in the light of day
这个家在阳光之下
zhè gè jiā zài yáng guāng zhī xià
This home under the beams of the sun
Let the storm rage on!
任风吹雨打
rèn fēng chuī yǚ dǎ
Let the storm rage on!
The cold never bothered me anyway.
反正冰天雪地我也不怕
fǎn zhèng bing tiān xuě dì wǒ yě bū pà
I don't fear the ice and snow anyway.